This is exactly how to build a highly
profitable lifestyle business. By the
end of this video, you're going to
understand how to build your team, how
to develop products, how to have the
right weekly activities, and how to run
highly profitable, highly successful
growth campaigns. I'm going to break it
down step by step so that you almost
cannot fail. If you get this stuff
wrong, you are going to end up as a
glorified freelancer with a few support
staff, and you'll never make a big
profit. You will always be on a
treadmill, and you will just feel like
business is such a drag. But if you get
this right, you will elevate yourself to
the level of a founder who owns a
business. The business will take on a
life of its own. It will have an amazing
dynamic team. You'll make loads of
profit. You can do this from anywhere in
the world and you'll have a new sense of
freedom that you've never experienced
before. The first element that we need
to have in place is to understand the
team dynamic that you're going to have
in your lifestyle business. Now, a
lifestyle boutique typically has 4 to 12
people. Businesses that have one to four
people, including yourself, tend to put
you in the role of highly paid
professional with a support team. Yes,
you're making lots of money. Yes, you've
got a few people helping you. But no, it
doesn't really feel like a business
where you could take some time off or
take a holiday. It feels like if you get
hit by a bus, the whole business would
stop. Now, once you hit the team of 4 to
12 people, everything changes. A 4 to2
person team means that you can play your
role as the founder and everybody else
can focus on their role to do something
important within the business. So let's
get in and have a look at what are the
key roles on the team. Now there are
eight key roles in a lifestyle business.
The first one is your role and this is
the most important role. I call this the
key person of influence. See the truth
is between half a million and 5 million
you've entered a phase called founderled
growth. Founderled growth is where the
business grows because of what the
founder does. In practical terms, what
this means is that you are the face of
the business. You are the face of the
marketing. You are going to be on
podcasts talking about the business.
You'll be up on the stage talking about
the business. You might write a book. If
you're running ads, you'll be the one
featured in the ad describing what it is
you want people to do. If you don't use
your personal brand, you are leaving 95%
of your firepower on the table. Having a
personal brand does not mean that you
share your private life. What you do
have to do is share the value of what
your business does. You need to share
the stories, the case studies, and the
intellectual property of your business
and make sure that it connects with your
ideal customer. The truth is that your
personal brand will get 20 times the cut
through as your business brand. I had
already built multiple 7figure
businesses that looked like this before
I had more than 20,000 followers. A lot
of people who have a sevenfigure
business with a six figure profit are
people who have 2 to 20,000 followers.
So long as they're the right types of
people who fit the description of your
ideal customer. You as the founder, you
are going to focus on what we call the
five Ps of pitching the business,
publishing content, creating new
products, raising your profile and
therefore the profile of the business
and doing strategic joint ventures and
partnerships. If you do those five
things, you're doing your job as the
founder. Now, here's what you're not
going to be doing. You're not going to
be running the business. The general
manager of your business runs the
business. The biggest question is, how
do I get myself out of the day-to-day
technician role and actually get into
this founder growth role? It normally
happens when you have a few key people
on the team. Someone who's good at
sales, someone who's good at helping
deliver the product or a general
manager. Just one or two good people on
the team and you can set yourself free.
Also, I really recommend don't think
about what you're not going to do. Think
about what you are going to do. Your job
is founderled growth using the five Ps
that I've talked about. Here's something
fascinating. If you go into a Starbucks
or a McDonald's, there's a good chance
that that's a multi-million dollar
business that is being run by a 24 year
old who only has a high school
qualification. Now, cafes and
restaurants are very hard businesses to
run. These businesses have razor thin
margins. They have a complex variety of
products. They have lots of young people
working who need training. All of those
things make it incredibly difficult to
run. And yet, a 24year-old on a normal
amount of money can run that business.
So, I want to propose to you that a
24year-old on a normal amount of money
could also run your business. You do not
need someone to quit their job at Google
to come and work with you and run your
business. You need someone who
previously ran a cafe, a restaurant, a
nightclub, or a hospitality business to
come on in and run your business. These
people are not crazy expensive, but
they're amazing at what they do. So, you
want a general manager to come in and do
everything that is hiring, firing, team
management, running the business, so
that you don't have to do that stuff.
and you can be that key person of
influence who drives the founder growth.
Let's look at the rest of the team.
There are three key elements to your
business. There's generating demand,
generating supply, and general
operations. Under your demand
generation, you're going to have someone
who's head of marketing and someone
who's head of sales. Those are the two
key roles. Now, you might end up having
two or three salespeople, or you might
have one or two marketing people, but
essentially, it's a marketing role and a
sales role. Under operations, you've got
finance and IT. and finance is going to
do all the stuff relating to the money
and it is going to do all the stuff that
relates to the data. And then over here
on the supply side, we've got the
product development and product delivery
team and the customer success team. So
product development builds a great
product and delivers a great product.
And customer success makes sure that
people are using that product
effectively and solves any problems that
happen along the way with a customer.
What are the products that you're going
to be selling? Well, you're going to
need something called a product
ecosystem. product ecosystem is four
products that are all nicely connected
together to form one smooth experience
for the customer. Now, if you only have
two of these products or three of these
products, you're going to be leaving
huge amounts of money on the table. You
need all four. You're going to have a
core product. The core product is the
main thing that you're known for. If
you're a consulting business, you're
going to offer consulting packages. If
you're an agency, well, you're going to
have agency services. If you're a
training business, your core product
will be a training package or a training
program. If you're a software business,
your core offering will be the
subscription to the main software
product, and it may even include a setup
fee. Before the core product, we have
two products that help to generate
demand. The first one is a gift.
Something for free that people can try
with no risk. They can download it. They
can engage with it. It might be a free
trial. It might be a free account. It
might be a free download. Something for
free that totally scales. It's digital.
It feels valuable, but as many people as
possible can access this free thing, and
it feels like they're getting an
immediate quick win. The next one is a
product for prospects. This is a small
commitment of either time or a small
amount of money in order to get started.
This could be maybe a workshop that
people do that's 90-minute workshop or
maybe it's committing to a 30-day trial.
A product for prospects could
potentially be a book that people buy.
Or my personal favorite is an online
assessment where people go to your
website and they fill out an online
assessment. Side note, if you've never
set up an online assessment, really easy
to do at my company calledcorapp.com. So
for example, if you do cyber security
consulting, you might have a cyber
security assessment that makes people
go, "Oh, I have a risk that needs
solving and now I need to get these
services in order to fix it." Now, after
the core offering, people are going to
want more from you because they had such
a great experience with your core
offering. They're going to want to stay
connected. They want to stay as a
customer. This is where we have a
product for clients. A product for
clients is typically a subscription
offering. It could be a membership or a
community or it could even be something
like an annual retreat. But it's
something that is special for your
clients and your customers to then go on
and upgrade to. If you have all of those
four products, each of them is doing a
job. One gets attention, one builds
trust, one delivers a transformation,
and one maintains great standards over
time. So those four products, they each
do a job. And the profit is not in any
particular product. It's in the product
and service ecosystem. Your core team's
job is to drive people through that
product and service ecosystem so that
the marketing and sales people are
getting people to go through the gift
and the product for prospects and by the
core product delivery and customer
success are going from core into product
for customers and the team understands
what the flow is and they understand how
to get people to go to the next step.
Now, by the way, if you're enjoying this
video, I'd love it if you'd give this
channel a like and a subscribe and maybe
leave a comment as well. I love the fact
that I get to share my entrepreneurial
lessons with you and I can in some way
help you on your entrepreneurial journey
and I would love it if you could share
this channel with someone else who's
building a business as well so that we
can all learn together. So we now have
the team and the products. Let's now
focus on the activity. The first
activity is the quarterly strategic
reset. The quarterly strategic reset is
where you get the whole team on an
off-site meeting and you get into a
boardroom and you actually set yourself
up for an amazing 90 days. You want to
make sure that you're really clear about
your priorities for the next 90 days.
You want to delegate accountabilities
and make sure the right person is doing
the right thing and that they've got all
the resources they need to get the job
done. You want to get each team member
to confirm and make a commitment that
they're going to play their role in the
next 90 days and they don't see anything
standing in the way. The quarterly
strategic reset can typically be done in
half a day to a full day and it's really
fun to get the whole team together in
one boardroom if you possibly can,
although you can do it on Zoom if you
need to. The next most important meeting
is the Monday morning meeting. Now,
another name for the Monday morning
meeting is the 3 to six thing meeting.
Every single Monday morning is the whole
team jumps on a Zoom call, take it in
turns for everybody to say what they're
going to do for the week. They're going
to give their three to six most
important things that they intend to
have finished by the end of the week.
Three to six things is about the right
number of things for people to declare
that they're going to get done and
they're willing to be held accountable
at the end of the week. At the end of
the week, we have a quick meeting which
is the Friday afternoon debrief. And the
Friday afternoon debrief is where we go
through and we recap what each person
said they were going to do on Monday
morning. And then they say done or not
done. They don't have to give big
explanations, but they do have to say
whether they got that thing done or if
they failed to get it done. And just
that little bit of accountability is
enough to make sure people got their
things done even if it was in the 11th
hour. What also typically happens at
these meetings is a little bit of
conversation where you might challenge
each other or remind each other of
priorities. Uh it's a time to check in.
It's a time to make sure that there are
two times throughout the week where the
whole team is together talking about
what needs to be done. Okay. The next
activity is to commit to having one
communication channel. This is one place
that all the communication is going to
happen. For a small team, you may use a
WhatsApp group where all the members of
the team are in that WhatsApp group and
the constant nattering happens in the
WhatsApp group. Uh for a bigger team,
you may want to invest into something
like Slack where you've got multiple
channels and a few extra tools and those
sorts of things. It's a little bit
fancier, a little bit nicer, but
essentially it's just one communication
channel where nothing gets lost. It's
all in one place. I've seen plenty of
successful teams operating in a WhatsApp
group, sharing files, sharing links,
sharing communication. You don't have to
overthink this, but here's what you
don't want to have happen. You don't
want to be scratching your head
thinking, was that an email? Did that
come to me on WhatsApp? Did that come to
me on Slack? You want to make sure
there's just one place where all the
communication goes through. And also
it's really nice for the whole team to
have transparency and to see what's
being discussed. The third thing that
you need to decide as a team is your
tech stack. Your tech stack is going to
include all of the software
subscriptions that you're going to
subscribe to. You're going to have an AI
provider. You're going to make a
decision between all the Microsoft
Office products or perhaps the Apple
products. You're going to pick a CRM
system for managing the relationships
with your clients. And you're probably
going to have some tools that help you
to generate leads and make sales. And in
fact, scoreapp.com is absolutely perfect
for running a lifestyle business through
because all of this thinking is the same
thinking that goes into score app. I
also want you to make a decision to be
extremely careful as to how you store
all your documents and files. I want you
to have a file storage system so that
everybody knows where to file things
away. If you've got media assets, they
go into the right folder. If you've got
databases, that's filed away in the
right place. If you've got slide decks
that you regularly use, then they're
always up to date and they're always in
the right place. With a team of four to
12 people, it's easy to create a mess if
people are not committed to filing
things away in the right place. And then
finally, I want you to have a dashboard,
which we call the sleep at night
dashboard, or what we call the sand. The
sleep at night dashboard is everything
that you need to know about your
business in order for you to sleep at
night, that it's safe, that it's okay.
So, in the sleep at night dashboard, you
might keep things like cash at bank,
number of people on the database, a red
flags or issues list, upcoming
milestones that need to be achieved.
Whatever it is that would keep you up at
night, you want to keep that on the
sleep at night dashboard so that doesn't
keep you up at night. Okay. And the
final thing that is super important is
you want to run three campaigns for the
year. These three campaigns are the
campaigns that I've been running for
over 25 years and they always create
growth. So, let me walk you through the
three campaigns. The first one is called
the perfect repeatable week. Perfect
repeatable week is you pick a set of
activities that drive growth through the
business and it typically involves
generating leads, appointments,
presentations, and sales. In one of my
businesses, every single Wednesday, we
run a 90minute introduction workshop and
it generates leads, appointments,
presentations, and sales. In another
business, we have an online assessment
and we drive people to that online
assessment and leads, appointments,
presentations, and sales. in another one
of my businesses. We drive people to
creating a free account and it generates
leads, appointments, presentations, and
sales from there. So, what we're doing
here is we're having a particular way of
doing business and we just want to
repeat it and repeat it and repeat it.
Once a quarter, we do something called
the quarterly spotlight campaign. The
quarterly spotlight campaign is where we
do something special or different. It
might be a special event. It might be
sponsoring an event. It might be
launching a new product or a special
offer. So, for example, it could be a
Black Friday offer at the end of the
year. It could be an Easter special at
the beginning of the year. Uh it could
be a summer catalog that you've got
coming out. Whatever it is, you're going
to pick something special to do once a
quarter that is going to capture the
attention of your audience and it's
going to give you something new to talk
about. And finally, we've got the annual
big message campaign. The annual big
message is where we think about what are
the big insights that we want to share,
what are the big stories we want to
share, what are the big ideas that we
think people would engage with. And what
we're going to do is create lots of
content. So, we're going to put lots and
lots of short form content onto social
media. We're going to drive people to
long- form content so that they can get
to know those ideas even better, right?
And we're sharing our big ideas across
the annual big message. For example,
this YouTube channel is part of my
annual big message strategy that I've
had for this year. And you've noticed
that I've stepped up my game and I'm
sharing more ideas. There's short form
and long form content. So, what you want
to do is figure out what are the big
messages and where are you going to
share those messages to capture the
right audience for your business. Done
correctly, the perfect repeatable week
will give you consistent sales to make
sure that you have a baseline of
revenue. Quarterly spotlights will give
you that icing on the cake, that cream
on top. It'll give you those profit
spikes that happen throughout the year.
And an annual big message will build
your brand over time so that you end up
with followers and fans. So, this is
what it looks like to have a lifestyle
business. When you have these four
things in place, your lifestyle business
starts being absolutely wonderful. None
of this is about geography. You could
have a team of people who are working
all over the world. You could have some
people in Boston, one person in
Brisbane, one person in Bangalore and
one person in Birmingham. All these
people could be working all over the
world. These products, these don't have
to be physical products. These could be
digital products. It could be software.
It could be services. It could be
consulting. These could be intangible
products ideally that you can deliver to
an ideal customer anywhere in the world.
I love the idea that you begin with the
end in mind and you work backwards from
there as opposed to starting with what
you have today and trying to improve it.
Don't start with something that's a
little bit broken and see if you can fix
it. I want you to reverse engineer the
future, not forward engineer the past.
The next question I get is how big does
this business need to be? The typical
number for most businesses is for that
each person on your core team, you need
about $125,000
per person as a minimum in order for you
to stay profitable. So if you have four
people on the team, you need half a
million worth of revenue. If you have 12
people on the team, you need $1.5
million worth of revenue. And that tends
to be the flaw. What I like to do when
I'm launching a new business or if I've
bought a business is I like to do
scenario planning and financial modeling
to see what it takes to make a
profitable business. Now, I've given you
a back of a napkin version. But what I
like to do is have a spreadsheet that
has all of the costs and all of the
products and then it looks at what sort
of volumes of sales do we need to do in
order to make sure that we're
profitable. with a decent spreadsheet
and some sensible assumptions, you
should be able to get the exact numbers
that you need to achieve in order to
achieve profit and that you have a
crystal ball that tells you exactly
what's going to happen at every stage of
growth. Now, if you want to know how to
get to this, there are actually a few
steps that I talk about in this book
that get you up to the 4 to 12 person
team. I talk about an entrepreneur
apprenticeship. I talk about side
hustles. I talk about scout teams and
fire starting teams. And it's all in
here, part of the lifestyle business
playbooks. It's my latest book. It's all
my best thinking about the shifts that
are happening in the world at the moment
and how to approach those shifts. It
even takes you one step beyond this 4 to
12 person team up to a 30 to 150 person
team, which is a performance business.
If you haven't done so already, go to
Amazon and get yourself a copy of the
lifestyle business playbooks. It'll give
you a little bit more detail and
information about how to get to the 4 to
12 person business if that's something
that you're worried about. Hopefully,
you've enjoyed today's video and your
business is doing really, really well.